Synced & corrected by QueenMaddie
www.addic7ed.com
Previously on From...
This was Meghan's favorite spot.
You'll bury me next to them, right?
Of course. Frank.
The box. I can't do it.
How do you think people are gonna react
when you let Frank go?
Aren't you supposed to be talking to me
about the virtues of mercy?
Is that what you'd prefer?
Hey, I'd prefer not to put a broken man
in a fucking box to be torn
apart when the sun goes down!
But you built a guillotine
in the town square.
What do you think happens
when people realize
you lack the conviction to use it?
You take that and you make
whatever life you can out there.
So, you're telling me
I'm in a town I can't leave
and that every night
monsters come from the forest.
No one is trying to be cruel to you.
But you need to
understand what's going on.
Oh God. Tobey?
What are you doing?
I'm checking to see if they've moved.
- If what moved?
- The trees.
Have you seen the boy who
lives out here? We're friends.
If you see that friend of yours,
tell him Victor says hello.
Sara... just tell me what you did.
I left the door open.
All newcomers have to decide
where they're gonna live:
here in Colony House
or down in the town.
It's just part of how we do things here.
I'd like to take the both
of you, show you around.
Well, I wanna come.
This is about all of us, right?
- I wanna see.
- We need you to stay here
- and be with Ethan.
- Three, two, one.
Why are you doing this?
You guys barely know us.
It's just what we do.
Are you living in town or Colony House?
Town.
- Julie.
- Colony House.
- Why are you doing this?
- Girl made her choice.
I appreciate everything
you're trying to do for me.
But the only two things that
I love in this world are gone.
I wanna see my girls again.
You know how sometimes
you dream and you forget,
but then, later, you start to remember,
and you realize that it wasn't a dream
and that all of it maybe really happens?
Uh, um...
I think I'm starting to remember things,
things that I thought were dreams.
I made you a drawing.
You can keep it if you want.
Well, good morning, sleepy head.
It's about time you woke up.
Can I have my pillow back?
Your... Oh, I'm so sorry.
Someone just gave this to me
last night. I didn't realize.
Oh, no. It's totally fine.
I just want to take a nap
and it's sort of like a security
blanket for me, you know?
Yeah, I totally get it. I'm sorry again.
Don't even worry about it.
Mi pillow, su pillow, or something.
Her name's Meredith.
Oh, the pillow. You named your pillow.
Uh-huh.
The things that matter to
you should always have names.
Yeah, totally.
You know, it's kinda funny,
I have a shirt just like that.
Oh, I know, I got this
out of your suitcase.
What?
You don't mind, do you?
We share everything here.
I guess not.
Thanks for taking care of Meredith.
Jesus.
Hey.
You sleep?
Yeah, I think so. I made some tea.
Let's get some light in here.
Oh, please no. Not yet.
Okay.
I used to love this time of morning.
I remember.
Sometimes he'd stop crying
just as the sun was coming up.
It was like he was saying...
"You've been up all night;
my work here is done."
Do you think we're being punished?
Why would you say that?
Jim, I'm drinking tea
out of a dead woman's mug,
in a place that can't possibly exist...
in a house where another child died.
Julie's off doing God knows what.
What are we gonna do?
I don't know.
Are you crying, Mom?
No, honey. I just...
I just have a headache.
Come here.
Sit in my lap.
I miss Julie.
Hey, why don't we
go down to that diner?
The sheriff said they serve
a big community breakfast
there every morning.
What do you say? You hungry?
- Yeah.
- All right.
- Let's do that.
- That's a great idea.
Yeah, you can...
You can go and-and
bring me something back.
What are you gonna do?
I, um... I'm going to...
I'm going to unpack.
Just organize our stuff.
- You sure?
- Yeah.
Okay. Saddle up, partner.
Let's go get some pancakes.
You think they'll have pancakes?
Well, I've never been
to a diner that didn't.
What are you gonna get?
Guess I'll have to look at the menu.
Do you think they'll
have whipped cream?
Uh, well, we'll soon find out.
Hi, Sheriff!
Uh, morning. Where are you
two fine gentlemen heading?
Oh, we're just off to get breakfast.
What's in the cart?
Uh, nothing. Just, uh, some supplies.
Gotta go over to the church,
take 'em to Father Khatri.
Do you need help?
No, thanks. You should hurry on now.
Mrs. Liu is very strict
about breakfast hours.
Don't wanna miss it.
All right. You have a good day.
- Take care now.
- Okay.
Hi there.
We were hoping you'd come by today.
Mrs. Liu always likes to try
and make something
special for our newcomers.
Ah, that's... Thank you.
That's very nice.
It's appreciated.
- I'm Sara.
- Jim Matthews.
And you must be Ethan.
I heard all about your heroic adventure
out in the woods the other night.
Come on, you guys can sit at
our very special VIP table.
Do you have pancakes?
I'll have to check
with the boss and see.
Mrs. Liu is kind of a genius.
She could probably
make a Salisbury steak
from a tire iron.
Liu...
she's the one with the husband the...
the other night in the clinic?
Right. Yeah, that was... um...
- I'm sorry, I shouldn't...
- No.
- I shouldn't...
- No, it's okay.
I, um...
I should go check on those pancakes.
Told you they'd have pancakes.
They don't leave much, do they?
Just make sure he's
buried with his family.
Yeah.
You're not coming back for the service?
I'm sorry, is something funny?
You gonna mention in your little service
how you're the one who wanted him dead?
Feel better now?
Hm?
Just bring back the
cart when you're done.
Uh, Jade?
Jade.
I, uh...
I knocked on your door to
get you for some breakfast.
What are you doing out here?
I wanna show you something.
That? That's, uh... That's empty.
Yeah. That's kinda the point. Come on.
Okay.
I thought it was some
kind of CGI party trick.
There was this... They were right here,
there was this weird fucking
symbol right on the ceiling.
And over here, right?
This is where the body was.
It was a guy right here. Dead, right?
Fucking half-crushed by this giant...
Giant boulder thing! And
then, he starts screaming!
Don't. No, come on.
Don't look at me like
I'm fucking crazy, okay?
I know what I saw!
I'm not. I'm not. It's just...
Look, the first couple
days can be really tough,
for everyone.
- No, no, no!
- It's like your brain can't really
understand what's going on and...
Listen, I wasn't hallucinating, okay?
Trust me, I've done a fuck ton of drugs,
I know what hallucinations
feel like. This was different.
It was here and then it wasn't.
I have a pretty healthy
imagination, okay?
I mean, I built a software company
based on nothing but
imagination. But this?
None of this is...
There has got to be an explanation
and none of you fucking people
seem to be looking for it.
Okay. Um, why don't we go
back to the sheriff's station?
'Kay? I wanna show you
something now. Come on.
Come on.
Whoa.
What do you say?
Thank you!
Enjoy!
Oh, I'll... I'll just take
a little bit of his, thanks.
- Pretty good, huh?
- Yeah.
See? Not everything's so bad here, huh?
Do we live here now?
No, no.
No. Uh, we're just
here for a little bit.
You know what? Think of it
like, um... like a vacation.
I think it's probably a quest.
What?
Like a hero's quest?
Like Norman had to go
on to the Lake of Tears?
We probably have to save
somebody if we want to go home.
That's what Norman had to do.
Yeah, you might be onto something there.
Sometimes I pretend
that's where Thomas went.
What?
That he's on a magical quest,
and if I try, I can help
him save the kingdom.
Is that right?
Um... Look, uh...
I'm gonna go to the
restroom for a moment.
You just sit here and hang
tight, okay? I'll be right back.
Hang tight.
Excuse me, where's the, uh...
Four inches.
What?
The trees,
they've moved four inches.
Is that good or bad?
They're close, so it's bad.
Should we tell somebody?
Oh, I don't think they'll understand.
There's something I need to show you,
something very important.
You remember the boy that
you were talking about?
The one that lives outside?
Is that him?
Who drew this?
I did.
But it's in crayon.
So?
You're a grown-up.
Is it him or not?
That's him.
What's wrong?
That means he was real.
Hey.
Hey!
It's okay, Dad.
Let me see that.
- I'm sorry.
- Hold on.
- I wasn't...
What is this? What're you doing?
Excuse me.
Dad, stop! What are you doing?
- Dad!
- You don't come near him.
You don't talk to him.
Do you understand me?
I would never do anything...
The only thing you say
right now is "Yes." Okay?
- I'm sorry.
- He's a kid.
Stay the fuck away from him.
Dad!
Why'd you do that?
Time to go.
Come on. Let's go.
There you are. Been
looking everywhere for you.
What's wrong?
Um, I think maybe I made a mistake.
It was hard for me too at first.
Tell you a secret...
It helped once I figured out
how to get my clothes back from Trudy.
How did you know that...
Well, she's wearing a new T-shirt
and I know she didn't
order that online so...
Come on.
Up, up, up.
Take it easy on that leg or
you're gonna pop a stitch.
You shouldn't have done that.
Victor's my friend.
Look, I'm sorry.
Just leave me alone.
You see that one right there?
- Which one?
- The black one, right there.
- Uh, yes.
- That one is Armani.
It belonged to this guy
Charlie, from Duluth.
Oh, God, he was this
amazing cross-dresser.
Oh, he was so beautiful and funny.
Ah! Anyway, when he...
Well, Trudy got her hands on it,
and now she's always trying to hide it,
so she doesn't have to
share it with anybody.
Since you're on laundry detail...
It's up for grabs.
It's up for grabs! Here, put it on.
I've never worn Armani before.
Well, I think Charlie would agree
it would look much better
on you than it does on Trudy.
Stop it.
Ms. Matthews!
It looks nice!
What?
If you want, I can go talk...
No, it's fine. I got it.
Hey.
Hi.
What are you doing up here?
Well, I found your sweater in my bag.
We miss you.
I miss you guys. too.
Then come back with me.
Honey, this is not a prison.
You can leave whenever you want.
We'll...
We'll talk to Donna about,
you know, you made a mistake,
that you've changed your mind.
I did...
Why do you always do that?
- Do what?
- You make it seem like
poor, stupid Julie doesn't
understand what she's doing
and that everything will just be okay
once I admit that I was wrong,
like I always have to do.
I didn't say that. I didn't say that.
Yeah. You know what? Forget it.
I really don't want to do this.
Hey, hey, hey, hey, Julie. Julie.
We have no idea where we are,
how we got here.
We have to stick together as a family.
Are you kidding me?
You're seriously gonna stand there
and lecture me about family?
I knew.
I knew what you and Dad were planning.
I knew all about the divorce
and how this whole trip
was just one last hurrah
before you sat us
down to break the news.
So stop treating me like I'm a child.
Okay, okay, Julie.
You're right.
Look, your father and I
love each other very much.
We love you and Ethan very, very much.
Thomas is dead! Okay?
And I know that it's hard,
and I know that you
lost, but we all lost.
You have two other kids!
Why aren't we enough for you?
It's not that simple!
I can't do this right now. Please, I...
I'm not trying to make
this more di... I'm sorry.
- I'll make sure she gets it.
- Yeah. Yeah.
What the fuck is this?
This, near as we could guess,
is where you and your
friend were driving
when you reached the tree.
But the RV that the family came in?
They were driving here.
- Okay.
- Me and my parents,
we were in Austin, Texas.
Kristi, the medic? She was in Detroit.
Every single one of these
pins is a different resident
who drove in from a different location.
Yet somehow we all ended up here.
That is fucking impossible.
Yeah.
Okay.
All right. Well, see?
That's the difference
between you and me.
- I don't do impossible.
- Right.
I don't just sit around,
accepting the world as it is!
Someone is doing this,
and I'm not gonna rest
until I figure out how.
Well, then you're gonna
lose your mind. Okay?
Because that's what happens
to people who can't adapt.
They can't bend,
so eventually they break. Jade, look,
every new person who
comes here just assumes
that it's just the monsters
they have to be afraid of,
but that's not the hardest part.
It's what this place does to you,
what it makes you think and feel,
what it makes you question
about every single thing
that you think you know,
and-and if you can't if you...
Yeah, it does that sometimes.
Look, I'm just trying to tell you,
if-if you can't understand that...
What are you...? Wait,
where are you going?
Jade!
Well, you look how I feel.
Ethan's mad at me.
Why?
I, uh...
I thought you were gonna unpack.
Yeah, I was. But I went to see Julie.
How'd that go?
Well, as well as you'd expect.
She knows.
What?
She knows about
the fucking divorce, Jim.
She fucking knows.
Everything's gonna be okay.
Oh, please stop saying that.
- What do you want me to say?
- I don't know!
Say that-that you're...
That you're hurt, that you're scared.
That this is all so fucked that
you have no idea what to do,
because I am walking around,
reminding myself to breathe,
and every time you talk about
how things are going to be okay,
it makes the rest of us feel
that we're doing something wrong.
That's not fair!
Fair?
I'm sorry, what part of the
last 14 months have been fair?
I'm tryin' to keep
a grip on things here.
It's not gonna do us any
good if we get hysterical.
No. You don't get to do that.
I am not being hysterical.
We wouldn't even be here if we hadn't...
What?
Just forget it.
Go ahead and say it. Say it to my face.
What was this trip
supposed to do, Jim?
What did you think was gonna happen?
That we were gonna go
camping for a few days
and everything would
just magically get better?
I'm sorry that I wasn't
just ready to cut and run.
Hi.
What are you doing out here?
We gotta go find him.
The boy?
Yeah. I mean, he's
been gone a long time,
and we need to ask him why he's back.
I'm not supposed to leave.
Oh, but you have to
'cause he chose you,
just like he chose me once.
Like a quest?
Yeah.
Okay.
But you can't take that.
- Why?
- Hm. No.
They're no good.
Those are for hospitals.
Yeah. That's better.
These are for quests.
Don't you need one?
Well, I've got this.
Yeah.
Let's go.
You know, if you need to
say shitty things to me
in order to feel better
about what happened, fine.
I'm not having this conversation.
Okay. In that case,
you're getting a sermon.
How 'bout Psalm 23, from the book of
"Cut the Self-Pitying
Bullshit and Be a Leader."
Look, what happened to Lauren
and Meagan wasn't your fault.
Frank putting himself in
this box wasn't your fault.
None of this is really
about them, is it Boyd?
You're gonna want to be very,
very careful about what you say next.
Or what?
You can't keep punishing yourself, Boyd.
She wouldn't have wanted that.
Hey! Hey! You are way
the fuck outta line!
You hear me?! Way the fuck outta line!
Before you got here,
I was burying more people in a week
than you've seen die
in the last two years.
But you were the one
who found the talismans.
You created order from chaos.
You made it possible for
people here to live again,
not just survive.
You saved this town, Boyd!
But the price you paid...
I can still see her face
when I close my eyes.
- Look...
- I can't even imagine
what it must be like for you,
and I wish you had the luxury
of grief, but you don't, Boyd.
These people need you.
We went three months
without a single death,
and there's been six
in the last three days.
People are scared. Okay?
The edges are starting to fray.
You need to be the one to
tell 'em it's gonna be okay.
Look, you want to use
me as a punching bag?
You need a place to put all
your anger, all those regrets?
Fine!
But they need you to be strong,
to hold this place together.
You need to be the one
to lead these people home.
'Cause if you don't...
she died for nothing.
And that's where the sermon ends.
Come on. Come on.
It's been so long
since he went away,
I started to think it was just a dream.
The first time I saw him was
right before the two cars came.
Not your two cars. The first two cars.
When was that?
Oh, it's been a while.
I wasn't much older
than you when they came.
Really?
Mm-hmm.
You've been here a
pretty long time, huh?
I've been here the longest.
For a long time there was
nobody else here but me.
How did you get here?
Mm. We shouldn't talk about that.
What happened to your parents?
I just said that we
shouldn't talk about it!
Sorry.
I used to have a little brother.
His name was Thomas.
He died when he was a baby.
Why'd you tell me that?
Because we're friends.
I don't want to know that stuff.
Why not?
- Hey.
- What's the matter?
Hey.
Look.
There he is.
We gotta go, we gotta go.
Tabby, can we just figure this out?
No, no, no, no, no, no.
I can't do that right now.
I really can't. You know what?
I'm... I'm gonna take
Ethan to see Julie. Okay?
We'll talk later. Ethan!
Ethan!
Ethan, sweetie, where are you?
Oh, my God, Jim!
Ethan?
Ethan!
Where did he go?
Look. A farway tree.
What is that?
Watch.
What's supposed to happen?
Oh, could be nothing or it could be...
H-how does it do that?
I don't know. But guess what?
- What?
- It works for people, too.
Really?
Problem is
you never know where you'll end up.
It could be somewhere close,
it could be somewhere far,
or it could be that
you end up stuck inside
a mountain somewhere.
They're temperamental that way.
Are there more?
Oh, there's a bunch.
I've never seen this one before.
So, now what do we do?
No.
What's wrong?
Don't you hear that?!
No.
Come on. We... we gotta go. Come on.
Ethan!
Oh, Jim.
Jim?
What's happening?
- Oh, my God. Oh, my God, Ethan!
- Mom! Dad!
Ethan, come, come, come!
Honey, come on, come on! Who is the guy?
Why are you with him? Are you okay?
Let me see you. Oh my God. Oh my God.
I warned you.
How's your leg? It's okay?
- I warned you.
- Please.
I fucking warned you.
I'm not a bad person.
I would never hurt anyone.
Dad, leave him alone!
Jim! Jim, he has a gun.
Sorry.
Jim, let's go! Let's go.
Jim.
Jim, let's go! He has a gun.
Don't ever leave the house.
Okay? Don't ever leave the house.
Sheriff?
Not Sheriff. Just Boyd.
'Sup?
Look, I don't mean to be a...
I-I got a problem.
This-this guy Victor,
up at Colony House?
Right. Look, Victor is
one of Donna's people.
The way it works here,
with the townspeople
and Colony House...
No, I'm... I'm not talking about
the way it works around here.
I'm talking about this guy.
He's... he's taken my kid
to the woods, he's
drawn pictures for him...
Right. Sorry about that.
I'll have a talk with Donna.
We'll make sure it doesn't happen again.
Do you know he carries
a gun in his lunchbox?
Jesus.
You may wanna mention that to her.
Yeah.
Anyway, I'll let you... get back to it.
Hey, Jim. Wait.
Listen, uh, look,
things around here have been a little...
Been a lot crazy ever
since your family got here.
We have not had a chance
to get to know each other.
Let's change that.
What are you guys doing for dinner?
Hey. Watch out.
- I can't...
- Okay, this way.
Okay, my God.
I'm so scared right now.
Just a couple more steps.
Careful, careful.
Can I please see?
Just a second.
Okay.
Okay. Now. Oh my God.
Now, before I take my hands off,
there's something I
want you to know, okay?
Okay.
Okay. Julie, there are
no mistakes, just choices,
and you chose what was right for you,
and that matters a lot.
Okay.
Madam Julie,
behold your very new
sleeping arrangements,
equipped with a cozy blanket
and your very own pillow.
- Oh my...
- Naming rights are optional.
But wait! There's more!
Ah, there is more.
Let's see.
Curtains for privacy!
Oh my...
It's all yours.
Thank you.
Come on.
- Thank you.
- Go.
Well, come on, try it out!
Oh my gosh!
- It's good, huh?
- I love it!
Seriously, thank you so much.
You don't need to thank
us. You belong here.
Yeah, you do.
And...
so does this.
Oh, honey...
Hamburger's good?
- Yeah!
- Yeah.
And Julie? How is, uh...
How is she?
Um, yeah, yeah, she's... she's okay.
Sure Ellis will take care of her.
Um, I've been meaning to say thank you
for what you did the other night.
Oh, yeah. Absolutely.
- Thank you so much.
- My pleasure.
My pleasure. You know, the
people in this town, we are...
you know, we take care of each other.
It's... It's like a family.
And, uh, given the circumstances,
you guys are doing fine.
- Yeah.
- Okay, here we go.
Special delivery for our newcomers.
Thank you.
We're VIPs.
Mm-hmm. I've never been a VIP before.
So fancy!
Do you wanna help me bring
over the rest of the food?
Yeah!
Oh, you're walking better.
Yeah...
They... They do that
sometimes. It's just, uh...
Sheriff, can I, um...
Hey, would you guys
excuse me for a second?
I just need to have
a word with my deputy.
* Crown and anchor me *
* Or let me sail away *
That summer in Texas.
* There is a song for you *
* Ink on a pin *
I'm sorry.
* Underneath the skin *
I'm sorry if I make
you feel like you're...
I just don't know what I'm doing
and I don't know how to do that.
But I-I never, ever
meant to make you feel...
I just feel so...
broken.
- And I, uh...
- Hey. No, no, no. Hey.
We're gonna figure it out.
We're gonna figure it out together.
Don't worry.
* Hell's the hippest way to go *
* Well, I don't think so *
Whatcha got there?
Sweet potatoes.
Ooh!
Sweet potatoes! Let's try it.
Nice family.
Now, there you go.
Come on. It's really good. Try one.
Do you think they're good?
_
Sara!
Hey. Hey, hey!
Oh! Oh, no, no, no. Okay, here!
Grab her... grab her arm,
grab her arm! Hold on, hold on!
Come on! Hold on. Hold on, baby girl.
Okay, Sara.
Victor!
What the hell are you doing?
You're freaking people out!
I was just trying to get
a head start this time.
Synced & corrected by QueenMaddie
www.addic7ed.com